hi Wendy
you want to unmute yourself you're the
first one here
you know how these masterminds go you
know lots of people sign up not
everybody shows up
but
so we're always giving it an extra five
minutes
so that people can come in hi Wendy
hi Cheryl
hi Paul
and mute yourselves quickly just to say
hi so I know you're actually there
I just saw you for a few seconds there
Wendy but you disappeared again so
I couldn't say hi
hi Sharon
and mute yourself for a second just to
say hi
hi edwardinski
great to see you again
yeah
how's meditation
I will unmute long enough to say hi I
don't feel like I can have my video on
but I'm so glad that you're having this
thank you so much oh so cool what what
triggered you most I mean I sent so many
different stories Regarding why I'm
doing something on salad
what triggered you
yeah that's a good question
I don't know I can tell you I'm I've
been paralyzed in bed with back pain for
three days so looking at the screen a
lot more than I might normally
um
yeah it was just in the top of my feed
in my email and
I'm not going anywhere so I clicked on
it awesome
and I would love to give you some tips
how to
disappear that back pain
super I'm ready to receive all right
giving it two more minutes for people to
show up
like I said it's always just a fraction
of the people who actually register who
show up but it's all beautiful because
um it will be on my YouTube channel for
people to review at a later time as well
anybody else want to tell me what
triggered them to be interested in
salads
seems such a mundane topic right
I can tell you that
I'm just a heavy salad eater I've been
vegetarian since 1984 and
got a certificate in natural hygiene
about
20 years ago the transformation
Institute and wow so you know Joe
Willard OH you knew Joe Willard no it's
name was Dr Neil starts with a d not
Sheldon
no no I know who Sheldon is but but no
that's not who was at the transformation
in the niadak was Robert saniyadak as
though oh I'd love to learn more anyways
um I'm a big salad eater I love salad
and I'm a grower I I teach um Farm to
Table I teach people how to grow food
and preserve food and
uh I just love fresh
um food and farmers markets are my
favorite place because I'm a farmer and
that's where my tribe is oh cool so
you're actually doing some of the
growing
that's that's my art and my addiction I
can't not grow in fact even in massive
restriction with no space I've got pots
of things because I just love it yeah oh
wonderful
I could I could use your help right now
I so want to grow a garden but I just
don't seem to find the time
um
okay
we are at the five minute mark
um first name last name would you like
to introduce yourself we don't know who
you are but I'm happy you're here
um ask to and I mean would you please
unmute yourself
I can't unmute you from here
no okay
it's fine too
all right all right so this is yet
another Mastermind with the mundane and
silly title what's in raw salad like as
if we didn't know what's in raw salad
right everybody knows what's in raw
salad
but
there's so much more to know and yes I
got that twinkle in my eye because
there's just so much behind this
title that we may not be
aware of
um and that's why I'm having this
Mastermind in particular
so just quickly who am I I'm Professor
Johanna Sophia of johanna's raw foods
and coaching and the Ross and life
project
check out Rossum life global
um
and
who else joined us right now okay
Monique is in okay
um and we
want to learn why I'm doing these
masterminds is because I love exploring
particular topics and
most of the time seeing how everything
is interconnected on this little planet
in this little universe that we call our
home
so
I'm going to start with the big question
what is food
what is food if anybody wants to chime
in
I always like to see your faces and I
always like to hear your
um when you're saying in the chat
sunlight yeah can be food is actually a
necessary ingredient for all food
but let's just stick to what we
say is food
some matter that provides nutrients
right and energy yeah exactly
um Sharon is saying
two any kind of living entity on this
planet so everything on this planet that
is growing and dying
requires
nourishment and we call that food the
bee has a different kind of food from
the giraffe and the Elephant has a
different kind of food from the mouse
and even though we have stories about
them you know there may be different the
lion has a different kind of food from
the deer and so forth and so forth
um
and just to take a little bit of a
broader look so we have all these
species on the globe that live that are
live entities from a flower to
a elephant
from the tiniest little insect in the
ground to the largest trees in the
forests
we have all these live entities what do
they have in common how do they all
absorb their nutrients
and we get to a very simple answer 11
million species are we don't really have
the exact number because there's so many
subspecies among all these tiny little
critters right especially the ones that
we've hardly even explored in the earth
and in the air and the ones that we can
only identify under the microscope
Etc so what do they all have in common
they absorb their food how
oh you know my my
cats always have little barbecue parties
and they invite the neighboring cats and
then they roast their mice over the fire
and
um my
my dogs
get the pot on the fire and put their
food in there and what else the ants
have little parties
where they
what do they do they bake things in a
solar oven Underground
all right what am I trying to illustrate
here how do they all consume their
nourishment their food
any answer
Wendy says I believe we don't need to
eat
um well that is that is a very
questionable
statement of course we can fast we can
Etc but the limited periods of time and
of course we also absorb nutrients from
the air and like you said sunlight from
the air
um in particular
because there's a lot of living entities
in the air what's in the air that's
alive
tiny little trillions of bacteria and
what we call parasites and what we call
fungi and what we call all kinds of
things that are actually in the air if
they weren't in the air if the air was
sterile
we could not live in it
so
everything that we ingest to keep our
life going has to be in what format
that's really what I'm asking
do the cats the wild cats out there
really have their Grill party
does the giraffe pick a lot of grass and
take it home and cook a soup
here we go of course Wendy has the
answer
no all 11 million species or more
whichever they are consume their
nourishment their food Raw
why do you think that is
and why do you think humans started
eating dead food as opposed to live food
now I don't want to go too much into
that but we can see when we just observe
biology
that's really where I want to go next
um
when we observe biology out there
every cell every little entity every
bacterium every
Critter and every elephant for that
matter
ingests
nutrients so as to
grow new cell tissue
because life is in and of itself
the reproduction of new cell tissue the
biology of it of course you know there
may be
very well be the spiritual aspect and
the Consciousness aspect of it but as
far as the biology goes
we really
should all understand
but science is a very schizophrenic
world at this time in history or has
been for a while schizophrenic means
that this part of the understanding
doesn't translate into this part of the
understanding right here we believe that
it's all just dead matter reacting to
something and here we we believe that
um
that we have to modify the living plant
so that it grows differently so we
acknowledge that it is alive and grows
um
so when I have
anything
that is food for other
species on this planet
it is consumed by all other species
alive because that's of course we then
can argue that's where the nutrients are
most dense that's where we can actually
where our biology is ready to absorb all
the minerals and the vitamins and the
phytonutrients and the fungi and the all
the things that we need
are in those living
things that we ingest
now we can also argue some of us
of all our species some of us species on
planet Earth
have the biology to digest
other living
entities as in larger creatures
we call them carnivores
so when a carnivore consumes
a smaller animal that is a biological
process for the digestion of that animal
and I'm just going to cut to the chase
you know in my lectures I do
these drastic little stories taking
people into this world of going out and
punching a rabbit with your teeth
um
when a carnivore swallows
another piece of Flesh or a whole living
animal
how does that carnivore creature then
swallow that whole thing and how does it
digest that matter it does that by
having an esophagus that opens
think of the large birds think of the
lion think of the snake swallowing a
whole mouse or rat or depending on its
size of course
um
so some creatures actually have the
capacity of swallowing raw flesh and
again it's raw flesh that they swallow
even the hyena
um doesn't cook the food even though you
know they prefer dead creatures rotting
creatures they get all the maggots and
all of that stuff in there that's alive
as well of course so when a carnivore
swallows
the
the skin the bones the
um the tissue the the cartilage of that
other animal and the flesh is digested
by what
we kind of all know that
acid
carnivores have an enormous amount of
acid in their stomach and it's
hydrochloric acid for the most part what
does hydrochloric acid do if anybody
gets it on their skin
as concerns humans in particular because
we don't have a dense fur that protects
us it melts the skin
it literally you know we call it burn
because it looks similar to fire burn
but it literally melts the skin and
that's why you know we have humans have
used
acid as a weapon against other humans
so
carnivores however have so much
hydrochloric acid in their stomachs that
they can melt that other creature and
digest it in that way and it's a very
fast digestion process not the slow
process of herbivores so just to round
that out so all creatures are
divided into categories of how they
digest and we just typically only
mention the two categories carnivores
and herbivores and the human species
clearly falls into the herbivore
category very clearly we don't have the
acid we don't have the esophagus that
opens up we don't have the teeth to
actually tear a living rabbit with our
teeth we don't have the typical things
of a carnivore
and yes of course then people say well
that's why we started cooking so that we
could eat
animal flesh flesh
flashing flesh
that we could eat that flesh and swallow
it break it down into smaller pieces
swallow it and digest it because
herbivores contrary to carnivores have
more digestion digestion using enzymes
so we use more enzymes the carnivores
uses more
acid all right so just to get that out
of the way
that is another reason or maybe one of
the reasons why humans started cooking
um
burning as in grilling baking as in
Heating in a confined space
boiling again you know cooking we call
that in general
Etc so that
those materials that our body is not
made to digest
could still be used for nourishment now
they will never ever meet the category
of
nutritiousness that
we have when we eat
the food that our body is made to or
designed to whichever you know doesn't
really matter who invented the human
body yeah
I think we did
we went outside the body
um
but yeah so we actually have the
constituency
of an herbivore with the long intestines
and the enzyme digestion and
we need
plant food now of course with the
cooking of animal flesh and with the
cooking all together and with the
preserving Foods in the colder areas of
the planet and probably there were times
when the whole planet was colder or the
whole planet was hotter you know we're
only just beginning to understand that
there were other eras on planet Earth
with high cultures mind you
um where the planet looked very
different
it doesn't fit well into the current
narrative that we still like hold on to
for dear life that we are the best ever
especially we the Europeans ha ha ha
I I learned relatively early that that
is not the case so
raw salads what's in our raw salad so we
could say that the best food that humans
could eat we Define as salad right oh
that's all you eat salad all day it was
just what my friends would used to say
to me
um because this is what we consider a
salad right I mean this looks relatively
pretty now but that's what salad has
been reduced to being
lettuce tomatoes cucumber for the most
part in every Diner in the US and
Europe Etc so that's your basic salad
however
since we could eat
oh dear I need to let dairy in
hi Dairy and welcome so we're in the
middle of
what's in your salads we're actually
just getting to what's in your salad
what's in the American diet what
happened to the American diet yes we
have reduced our salad to this and
statistics have it that
I don't know a large percent I think 30
40 percent of American citizens
don't eat any
fresh raw food
other than maybe an onion running on
your burger or or one lettuce leaf on
your burger or a slice of tomato here
and there
and in some cases
people don't even eat plants
or or rather vegetables what we consider
vegetables right because fruit
well if it's in your strawberry ice
cream if it's even real strawberries
that are in there
um
but your
your onion rings on your burger on your
white bun Etc are so little that the
human cell tissue cannot properly
replicate
and you know to get back to the biology
that's what we kind of have done to
ourselves in
the advanced highly processed
Supermarket diet
um that we have deprived ourselves of
exactly what
enables us to reproduce cell tissue
easily and function in the world without
dis ease all the time
now I don't need to tell you I'm sure
all of you are aware that dis-ease has
become the biggest business in the
Western World right especially in this
country so when dis-ease becomes a
business obviously it's in the interest
of those who own those businesses to
have us be diseased so that they can
offer us something to supposedly make us
more at ease or we call that than health
but
it has to collapse itself again and
again with other side effects Etc to
keep us in disease because a business
needs to maintain and grow it's business
right
boom there it is
um
so true
thank you
but back to why raw and what do we want
I have a lot of things here on my desk
you know when you when I'm I'm going to
show you in a minute
because
life on planet Earth actually remains
raw all the time until there is a death
of one species and even out of that
death out of the decomposition arises
New Life of some form different species
probably and I wanted to show you
what's in my salad because this is
always the most clear evidence
why do we want our plants to be alive
when we consume them look at this onion
some people think oh don't eat the onion
when it's growing it's not good anymore
I never understood why that would be the
case
you see how it's growing
and actually I just cut it half an hour
ago
and now I cannot press it back together
because it is already growing bulging
out of here and these Sprouts are
growing further so we want to actually
consume this onion while it is alive and
um
and that is true for everything that's
on my desk here and behind me in that
big bowl and I'm going to go into that a
little bit more but I wanted to give you
the background now what does that
understanding that we need Rose salad
have to do with politics a little bit I
mentioned is the medical industrial
complex that does not thrive on
us being healthy
exactly
um but we have of course also gone into
broad agricultural industries that
intentionally will take away
natural food growing from a population
and plant mono crops because again
that's the business model of our
Agriculture and of our medical complex
and of our
military complex Etc so we want
monoculture in this phase in history
hopefully we're going to get out of it
soon but we're still in it where we
literally
desertify we create deserts
because we extract the nutrients without
allowing the Decay to revitalize the
soil and
the whole system
and that can be shown by a way of this
what we actually call desertification of
whole Landscapes the the earliest very
man-made example of that is which most
people don't know is the Dust Bowl
in the American history in the early
1900s that those were the first couple
of decades where heavy chemicals were
used on agriculture nitrates and other
chemicals to
create fast growth of and taller growth
of plants and large swaths of monocrops
and that caused actually the complete
deaths of the soil
and allowed the winds to blow over the
entire middle American region that
became the Dust Bowl
um you know at first when we first
learned about it we learned that oh it
was a natural disaster you know these
kind of things happen
but it wasn't it was the first chemical
agricultural
expect well it wasn't even an experiment
because they were so convinced and you
know for a few years it really brought
these huge yields Etc
and then of course
the deprivation of the soil
caused that the end of that
um that culture
um
a couple of words for the soil the soil
good soil
is of course in and of itself an entire
an entire culture of Critters
top soil which is where most of the
nutrients come from for plant growth
is alive
when it's good soil
and again when you when you use too much
chemicals pesticides and herbicides in
particular
you kill of course pesticides kills
insects and these tiny little entities
in the soil are the first ones to die
because they're even smaller than your
bees you know we're all concerned about
the bees yeah right we should be
but all the other much smaller Critters
that make
dirt into top soil into that dark
wonderful
crumbly matter in which the most
the best plants grow
when you kill that you basically kill
life on planet Earth
so then
you're even your lion can't find a
gazelle to eat because the gazelle
depends on the weeds
to be eaten that should grow in healthy
soil right so I mean even it could go
into the complete Wilderness we will
still find the same erosion of all of
life when we destroy
the micro life in our soil and the same
is true for the air in our air we have
the same
thing when when Wendy says but we can
we can live on without eating right
then I say yeah only because the air
when the air is alive when the air is
like we had a couple of days ago here in
New York when we had that incredible
smoke coming down from Canada if there
if that would have lasted for four weeks
and yeah maybe double the intensity of
it
you would have seen life dying
so
again when you start killing the micro
life then life ends now how come we can
all stay alive with so much cooked food
everywhere from China to Russia to
Germany to Africa to everybody Cooks
their food now and grills their
barbecues right let alone America
how do we even stay alive
and that feeds back into what Wendy was
saying that
we actually still have enough
life in the air and even in our
contaminated Waters and in those few
bits of raw food that people still get
to consume maybe there's an apple here
or there
because even your OJ your traditional OJ
doesn't have any life in it because it
is pasteurized right what does
pasteurizing mean
dead
I love being drastic and kind of
childish but
but that's yeah
that's exactly the point
so and of course our life is
substantially shortened
substantially all other mammals have a
life expectancy of at least 10 times
their sexual maturity age
and that would put us at at least 120
130 right because we don't really want
10 year old girls having babies right
which would mean sexual maturity and
allowing
um or anticipating that a 10 year old
can actually raise a family
so we should really look at 14 years and
indeed
140 150 160 would be normal human life
expectancy
have we had that only in very small
pockets of the globe in my lifetime
and decreasingly so because of course
now even the airspace even the the
Chemtrails and the waters and the clouds
and the ocean waters are beginning to be
so contaminated that it reaches
everybody
you know when we get these statistics
that 85 percent of all water
in lakes and rivers and creeks and in
oceans
are full of plastic for example
contain plastic particles
and other forever chemicals but I I
don't want to talk too much about
chemicals I want to get back to this
life force that actually allows us to
have this longer
well-nourished lifespan now I don't know
whether I can get there because because
my first 30 years were not that actually
my first 50 years were not really that
um so there's a lot of contamination of
course also our genetic
um material is
um is hampered or is
um what's the word
um is deteriorated if you will because
our parents had very poor diets and very
poor understanding of what is healthy
um and what is
otherwise a healthy lifestyle and then
of course we introduced chemicals but
we're not the first ones to introduce
poisonous stuff into our lifestyle
I do want to make that clear it's not
the last 200 years that for the first
time we were using poisons
what did the Romans use those of you
being with me for a while you know know
that I like to bring up these examples
what did the Romans have in their
culture
anybody
you have to unmute yourselves
I'm not seeing you can also put it in
the chat
how did they make their plates
and their goblets out of what material
with lead yes ma'am Wendy is the
Superstar here LED absolutely I was a
certified lead remediator Once Upon a
Time oh congratulations so you know a
lot about it yes but not the Romans were
also not the only ones using lead as a
main cultural
um material to make their whole plates
and and bolds Etc and something else
that they had in common with the
Japanese for example that the women
would make lead paste and put it on
their face or even eat it
to make themselves pale or translucent
in Chinese too
try these two the Chinese too
they did it there are several paints too
Chinese too yes yes yeah there are
several paints containing lead even
today I've oftentimes had dishware
especially coffee cups from Mexico that
look very
uh shall we say uh the clay in the color
looks very sort of natural indigenous
but the paint has very very heavy lead
in it it's not food safe and I I'm just
uh sort of an intuitive uh yellow canary
a canary in the coal mine and I can
sense it and it's just I've run into it
several times and then and actually
challenged people and they went and had
it tested and said you're damn you're
straight on right yes yes and so that's
just one example you know I like to
challenge people to come up with other
examples of where humans have surrounded
themselves with materials that were
toxic and poisonous and many of it was
that the those that were the wealthy and
the Emperors were the ones that had the
sort of special treatments and access to
them and they had their personal private
um Alchemists that were actually
introducing all these different harmful
chemicals that was actually killing them
their wealth was a
well there's downfall and it was
poisoning themselves through various
means taking it internally as well as
the makeup and things like that yes and
and it that's the that's the the irony
it was often poisonous the use of poison
was often a status symbol goodness
exactly
lead Cutlery and and plates and goblets
Etc you were of higher status exactly
the same is true for of course Chinese
food binding which would make make the
little girl's feet
literally brought alive because you know
when you when you have your toes growing
this way and you tie them the toes would
grow in like this and into each other's
flesh
it's I mean it's so gruesome you know if
anybody ever had a broken toe and knows
how painful it is to walk with that can
you imagine having all ten toes broken
and walking on that or being supposed to
be walking on that it's just it's
unbelievably painful
so
some say that's where opium use started
so you would also give those girls opium
so that they wouldn't faint all the time
um talking about fainting of course you
know we get to the core sets etc etc but
not to spend too much time on that there
was also arsenic that was used as
medicine and there was Mercury that was
used as medicine
for centuries
um so and I'm sure there's a lot more
that I don't even know about
that's what killed the first emperor of
China
Mercury
there you go yeah that was the magic
potion to make them live forever and
killed him oh
now you know a lot about Chinese culture
I believe right
a little bit yeah so yeah so
when you have Empires you create
cultures and often you make the culture
coercive so that everybody has to follow
that culture and if they don't they are
expendable
um
Expendable bodies that that you don't
want so you either find ways to kill
them or poison them or enslave them or
sell them etc etc
so
interestingly
just this morning because I've been
thinking about all these connections you
know with my raw salad stuff which I'm
going to still show you in a minute
um
and how it all connects of course with
our agricultural
customs and cultures around the globe
and just this morning I'm hearing
a
younger Zimbabwean
I think he's an economist actually and
and
he talks about his name is rotendo
I'd have to type him in here for you to
understand and he is talking in this one
interview he is talking about
how
colonists colonialization have
has taken away all the indigenous ways
of eating and doing Forest farming so to
speak doing growing with innate natural
settings all over the world
and then I said oh my God yes of course
think of the indigenous Africa the
indigenous Americans think of the yeah
the South Americans living in the
Amazons and
etc etc everywhere
people and I I met this Vietnamese woman
when I was work teaching in Germany for
a while
um who told me that yeah her mother
found all their food out in the woods
and the fields in nature and they were
eating it fresh and raw so it is not
something that us crazy
um new agers invented and suddenly we
want to eat only salad right it is
actually the original human food that
got contaminated but when when this
young man rotendo
was explaining how now the entire
African continent is deprived of its own
natural food growing and understanding
of how that works because just like all
over the Caribbean and and Latin America
you know the large food corporations
came in there and just flattened
everything group only corn only bananas
only cotton only etc etc monocultures
and always with chemicals
and now of course for the last 50 years
it's that's how long it goes back
already with genetically modified seeds
that are
engineered to to grow plants that in and
of themselves then are infertile so that
you have to keep buying
the next set of seeds
um so with all this going on Humanity
really shooting itself in the foot big
time because when you create infertility
on that scale what are you doing
you're eliminating life on planet Earth
in the longer run and there's a curve
that you know we just are hitting the
The Tipping Point and the curve gets
steeper if we don't counteract fast
so not only do we make ourselves
infertile and again you know I have my
personal story dealing with infertility
and finally having my two children and
so I have that experience and of course
in in Europe the
birth rates have been regressing for
decades
um but yeah we're doing it to ourselves
with these two crazy eugenicists
thinking that you know we are
overpopulated
um which is ludicrous
um
but what is more important is that we
need to understand that our really
original nutrients
have been
degraded to an extent that we need to
claim back plant life in a healthy way
and we need to claim back those
nutrients in their living
state
if we want to have a happy healthy life
and in a couple of months this lady over
here is going to be 70.
7-0
so
I am quite
proud of myself or you know only when I
look at other people and I
yes it is not nice of me to think
sometimes oh my God that person is
younger than I am
too bad but you know of course it's
ignorance and it's not knowing and
that's why I'm doing these masterminds
also because it is so easy and so
luscious and so incredibly wonderful and
we can create all the culture we want we
can have elaborate cakes and and drinks
and everything made out of fresh plant
life and that's why I wanted to do this
salad thing because it's the only thing
left that people know
is eaten raw
you know apples maybe but then you know
people make cooked applesauce and eat a
lot more of that than fresh apples
or they make apple pie again you know
then all right what's on my desk okay
I'm gonna tilt the camera
a little bit let's see hopefully
looky here
all this stuff is on my desk and what's
behind me in that big bowl over there
I'm gonna grab it and bring it over here
okay but here let us look
this is what I just brought in just
before
I started the Mastermind yeah
two wild plants that happen to be in my
backyard
that is
dandelion
um wild lettuce it's delicious yeah well
the end of line of course gets bitter on
its own but you're absolutely right and
then there is what is called garlic
mustard I'm sure it has a better name
but those leaves those little leaves
here and also these round ones here
are delicious you know when added to
your salads or your Savory smoothies
okay
then I have my regular of course you
know this is all Americans know as salad
romaine lettuce cucumbers and tomatoes
nothing wrong with them but the
nutrients are very minimal in there then
I have some peas here
wonderful whether they're fresh or
frozen
incredibly nutritious now what's next to
the piece I'm going to do a little later
now you realize they had to be cooked in
order to be frozen cannot have raw
frozen peas because
they don't they cook them to freeze them
really
it's not yeah if you study any freezing
especially commercial you have to what's
called parboil
you just freeze fresh food without
um
a lot of berries and stuff myself every
summer and they look just like
I do too but I can guarantee you
commercially they're not they are
parboiled okay so they're pasteurized
basically yeah and also I just teach
people how to preserve and I've been
told by the Wisconsin State Health
Department that I cannot teach people to
freeze raw food that's that's ridiculous
of course you know we I do it all the
time all right so here we have
blueberries strawberries raspberries
those are the most well-known berries of
course in the U.S but there are many
many many many more berries of all kinds
that are edible in up into the most
northern parts of the world and down
into the tropical
arenas
so here I have our favorite dressing
that is
actually
I always make homemade dressing because
I mean from dressing I do know that it
is definitely pasteurized when we have
um any kind of store-bought dressings
right those are always pasteurized
um
so this is
um very quickly
okay actually no I'm going through this
so that I can put my face back on so you
can see what I'm saying back here is
just as one example of raw tahini
and again I mean I don't think they
could say raw if it were also
pasteurized but then again
raw sunflower seeds are now called
raw even though they're pasteurized so I
wouldn't be and and of course I wouldn't
be surprised and of course pepper and I
use Celtic Sea salt it's not in the jar
that it comes in
but it also is alive because it contains
plant particles all right then we have
here nuts and seeds and of course there
are lots and lots of different seeds and
here we have something
that is a raw burger burger
so why is that raw because
if there were whole pieces of um
seeds still in here hold seeds they
would actually grow because it has not
been heated above 120 degrees back here
we have
mushroom cheese now cashews are always
debated as not being raw and still
there's a big difference between roasted
and the ones we call Raw
um that again have wild this is cashew
cheese with Wild Greens in it then we
have a raw apple sauce
makes I mean it's a great addition to
certain
um of course it goes Brown apples go
Brown when they're exposed to air right
to oxygen and here we have a pesto
it is also a wild crafted pesto let me
see
again it goes dark when it's exposed to
oxygen when it was fresh it was bright
green and it actually has garlic mustard
and
since it was frozen in the winter of
course just in the early days of spring
we have
um
we have chives wild chives out here a
lot
in big bunches wow that's that's what's
in in that pesto all right here we have
and again these are all just the
Northern Hemisphere plants
oh
man this is heavy look let's see
hail celery zucchini carrot there's a
mango in here
it's not quite ready yet
of course that comes from further down
south and there's lemon orange avocado
broccoli banana
cauliflower and a banana oh it's a
banana that's right you don't want the
banana republics and a green pepper and
of course green red yellow they're all
wonderful and so much more
um so
I wanted to take the time to ex at least
show you that there's a plethora of
plants
and this is just a tiny little excerpt
of all the plants that you can put even
in your salad or you can call all the
things you make in the Raw salad and or
dessert which of course is another
um another Mastermind that I need to do
on
oh and here's another example
of carrots that are not treated
this if I leave this lying around long
enough will grow little leaves again
carrot greens are very very tough so
even the Vitamix doesn't break them down
sufficiently but they're very highly
nutritious that's right so I don't know
maybe maybe juicing them would work
I would offer that when I cut the ends
off of my vegetables I always plant them
yes
also you you you're always ahead of me
here very good very good look what this
is wow yes and you can also just keep a
pot of dirt and just put it right in the
dirt too you don't have to have the
water first but sometimes it works the
easiest depending on your situation yeah
yeah I I mean I kind of know that but I
haven't gotten to the dirt box in my
house I think I think the problem is
that my my cat would jump into the dirt
box thinking that it's the right place
to poop because you know that's what she
does outside in the dirt
so I think that's the the biggest
problem but yeah this is actually rare
that these are so thin I mean most of it
maybe because the tops are very flat
they're very flat a little bit more it's
about how much light you're getting each
day mm-hmm
yeah yeah so yeah and that's that's a
romaine lettuce that is growing
plants there
yeah it's ready for a pot I'd bury that
sucker about a half an inch quarter inch
deep
yeah yeah so in any case
um that again is an example of the fact
that even the cut of pieces of a living
plant
um are still alive down tissue
in those pieces remains alive for a long
time
and that is why even you know in the a
couple of decades ago there was where
all these arguments you know smoothies
you're breaking the stuff down so far
that there's no life in them anymore
but I think there is because
the life of the cells is still there of
course you know some people would say I
just was listening to Dr Brooke goldner
you know when the cell wall is broken
apart then the nutrients are accessible
if you drink the Smoothie immediately
keep it cool
so we can we can argue those details
the bottom line is that ingesting all
these living plants even the ones that
we may think are not quite living
anymore but occasionally we add them I'm
just sprouting some garbanzo beans and
some Alfalfa as well so
even adding those will still
allow us to have a vital cell
reproduction in our bodies so make those
salads as luscious and as big and as
varietiesness that's not a word
variable
and different as you'd like or have the
same big salad every day some people
like
match what's his name would say I had
the same big salad with three avocados
every evening and I loved it for three
years or something like that it's all
good but ingesting those Raw
enzymes and that cell tissue that we
need for our body to stay alive longer
and stay well longer I mean I can't stop
my wrinkles or my flab on my arms but I
can feel
like I am just like when I was 30.
um there's one more thing that is very
essential in raw
salads and raw food all together and
that is what what's in here that's not
so much in the other plants we were
looking at
well it's
these nuts
seeds and nuts yeah hazelnuts walnuts
sunflower seeds in this case right nuts
and seeds have the fats that we also
very very much need especially for our
brain cells
and of course
we want to emphasize the Omega-3s that
are particularly in of course we know
about flax seeds and chia seeds but also
in walnuts in
sunflower seeds
and hazelnuts and of course also in
almonds but they have to be the the raw
ones
they're hard to come by in the U.S you
have to have special sources and my dad
I relied from my fat pretty pretty
heavily on avocados and coconuts being
that I live in Costa Rica the last seven
years and nuts prices of nuts and seeds
is extremely prohibitive Aida a little
bit of sunflower of a sesame seed uh to
make my own tahini and might put a
little bit of tea my own tahini in a
salad dressing uh and maybe every three
months I love to have something like
peanut sauce but besides that I don't
eat consumed seeds and nuts here except
rarely because it's just prohibitive and
I have easy access to avocados and
coconuts so I capitalize on those
now I'm curious Wendy even though we
need to rev up but um what do you think
caused you a backache
I have not been doing lots of physical
labor for oh goodness five years or more
and I just worked my ass off for like 10
days in a row doing lots of uh digging
and lifting and moving and extreme
weather conditions and I just wouldn't
stop and take care of myself and my body
said you're done
I hear you okay so that is a very good
explanation because of course if you
don't keep your muscle tissue trained
all the time and then stress it over the
top
it will tell you it will say Okay Wendy
that's it you're doing this no more
every day I had some excuse why this
thing was more important than my
self-care and finally my body called uh
called trumps on me
yeah yeah
and that is true but what you're saying
about um about prepared food is um
anybody who's been in raw food for a
very long time who's sincerely
authentically interested in health will
come to the conclusions that mono diets
and just straight unprepared food is the
best way to go in the simplest to digest
but most people have so much um
emotional and cultural and psychological
connection to food that that's the art
that's the Love Like I Do Love people
with food and I I could tell you that if
you're really dying of stage for cancer
yeah it's best to just do what I said in
eat just eat monomials one at a time but
if I want to love you with food I can
make these more complicated
um complex gorgeous like you said uh
appealing uh salads and beat cakes and
like I'm a gourmet raw food chef I I
could I'm doing plant talk talks on
plant milks and I'm an ice cream queen
I'm known for fruit leather uh a
dehydrator Queen like I can make all
that beautiful and people who are really
serious about their health
aren't those people but for me to Market
to those people I'm actually marketing
to people who are less serious to their
health and I felt that that bothered me
on a level you know as well
commercializing than people that are
actually transitioning there's a saying
in natural hygiene that if you're using
a transitionary diet to get to a place
that's great but if you're living in a
transitionary diet it's like green
washing it's like saying look I'm living
in a transitionary diet you're not
actually getting there so I see these
things it's kind of yeah I hear you one
day but I'm going to cut you off there
because I do have a different view on
what it means to be human in health and
what it means to be human means to be
creative and what means to be human is
to live in nature with nature be of
nature but also to create we could not
have art we could not have buildings we
could not have creativity yes that is a
way of living but to me it is very
important and to get to the joyfulness
of being and creating and that includes
the joyfulness of creating beautiful
food
um that is at the same time nourishing
and replenishing and I also I mean I see
the that's what Hippocrates Health
Institute does you know this very strict
um diet for the healing that's what what
Dr Brooke goldner does etc that's what
we all do for a healing phase
but then it is wonderful to live a full
life with a full expression in
everything we do whether it's decorating
our home you may see that there's a lot
no you don't see it in this there's a
lot of Art in my house
and of course we as Humanity develop in
these cultures that come and go
and to have cultures that are healthier
than older cultures is a wonderful thing
but I cannot take culture out of food
and be an intelligent human at the same
time that to me doesn't work so I love
Joe Willard Joe Willard was a natural
hygienist and you know it was on um WBAI
in New York the Pacifica Radio station
and had her you know would explain
exactly that what you were just saying
that you know eat your cabbage on its
own and eat your Apple on its own and
not together
I think that's
yeah it's silly so yes if it works for
you if you love that do it by all means
but the people who grow old
are the ones who are also highly
cultured one of my students in Los
Angeles was from the Arab Emirates was
it from Omar or one of the smaller
countries
and he said his uncle
lived in an oasis in the desert and
walked every day to the rest of the
family outside of the Oasis he grew to
be 132.
and
and was walking and participating in the
family culture Etc and that movement and
that walking and the culture that I
experienced in this student's family
because I was invited to them also
was just
wonderful so I think
culture is very important we just need
to be a little wiser in creating culture
I don't want to live without culture
because I think I'm living long because
I don't have the evidence I mean I'd
love to hear from you
um or you know email me
to tell me which people lived on mono
food eating long and happily I I just
don't see it
um
yeah Joe was Joe Willard was was
wonderful she was riding her bicycle
into her 80s
but yeah then she barely reached her 90
I think so to me that's also not old
um
I don't know whether I'll make it
obviously
but
um yeah to me that whole cultural
element is very important and that's
I mean I have these long discussions
with with Brian and Anna Maria Clement
you know of
why
why we humans are humans as opposed to
chimpanzees or dolphins for that matter
also highly intelligent creatures but
not
creative
um
and tell me if you disagree
so but of course we get into a whole
different
um philosophical question there
what is life as a human on this
beautiful planet I love this little
planet
yes
and I think
the human connection the creation the
togetherness the struggles we have with
each other to understand how different
we each are and to acknowledge that and
still to provide all this nourishment so
that everybody can have a better
functioning body is so important to me
and I also I really didn't mean to poo
poo the the mono Foods I just don't see
that they actually help health in the
long run
um so and I'm all flushed because I was
so excited about this particular
presentation I don't know why more so
than
many others that I've done
um
yeah because it's it's so both so simple
and so
deep understanding what food really is
and how World politics have taken away
food from humans and not only humans I
mean we've had we've had
many many thousands of species already
have gone extinct because of our
chemical farming and our let's speak the
big word are a capitalist system which
is ruining everything
we need to invent a different system all
right any more questions
Monique Ed
first name last name I was trying to see
if there's a name in there but there
isn't really potash Paul Sharon Dairy
shoot
I love answering questions
well uh Joanna thank you so much this is
Shirley yes I see you I
I grow
geraniums and nasturtiums I put those in
salads I had the onion flowers they were
in season for two months and they have
beautiful white flowers maybe that's
what was in your onions I couldn't see
at that time and I put those on flowers
I decorate my salads every salad has to
be a work of art
everything was you know separated and
then you took a little bit of this a
little bit of that but nobody really
tried to decorate to appreciate that and
sit in meditation and look at and when
you're taking small bites and
appreciating each little more sense that
you're eating
uh this uh really
uh makes you feel
so appreciated and So Satisfied
yeah thank you for saying that Charlie
and the the interesting thing is also
that when we enjoy food or when we enjoy
sites when we enjoy smells Etc when we
enjoy our essential experiences
we actually create
endorphins and serotonin and we
literally create longevity
yes using all the seven uh seven senses
and smelling them and one thing I've
been doing though to get enough exercise
in oh for cherries and I will do the
stand-ups 24 times out of my chair and
get the uh but I'm Jewish at the same
time
other ways I wouldn't get I do so much
exercise now because I fell last year
because of my eyes but I'm uh back to I
got a brace on now and I'm back to
improving myself I can do so much with
the brains and I am just this energetic
now right and you're up there in your
80s right yes late 80s
Bravo
congratulations Cheryl
Shirley
wonderful okay any more comments or
questions
oh
um
Joanna do you ever get cold though and
need some hot tea hot tea or something
that can warm you up like really
warm soup yeah I've noticed surely that
I used to be cold all the time because I
have very low blood pressure and a
little hole in my heart and you know as
a kid I was always cold and and that in
sports Etc but now that I exercise walk
or run regularly and that I drink more
water I think when we get cold it often
has to do with lack of hydration as well
so well I I drink 64 ounces up to 64
ounces I just have to urinate often but
I can't do that but Bravo yes but uh
that doesn't make me uh warm because I
also have the uh I was paralyzed as a
child but uh
so I do have some warm tea I have
oh my God
various I do too occasionally I make
myself a cup of tea so I I agree that
can be very
a very good thing to have a little pie
and pepper
off you know me I'm the Cayenne I am
queen clients called me
oh but you're the Cayenne Queen yeah
yes
high end in everything yes of course
those those hot foods have a healing and
a warming effect
which is ironic or not ironic actually
it's it's wise that hot foods are eaten
mostly in the hotter areas of the planet
because they of course also encourage
sweating and sweating calls
pulls down the body exactly yeah
so do you believe in Sun as then
in what saunas
believe in you know I don't like the
word believe oh at all
I don't know much about I mean the few
times that I've been in regular old
saunas I've always enjoyed it the um I
find the
the what are they called Sonos that you
just sit in with your head outside the
ultraviolet I think it is a what's it
called
what are those cultures
I put a sauna
there's a kind of tint one you sit in
yes
I thought that was I don't know I didn't
find that very exciting no but the
regular good old season the wood um
saunas I've done and and I've enjoyed
that a lot especially then jumping into
cold water
um so I think that's very useful
especially in the colder parts of the
planet
um
where
infrared sauna exactly yes that was the
name yes infrared sauna and of course a
lot of people swear by it and I'm sure
they're good
um but I don't personally
use them that much maybe you know
we all pick our battles I suppose and
pick our remedies right
yeah right if if you have
I mean there's so many great modalities
I was really really happy to find Wim
Hof and those breathing exercises
incredibly helpful oh also helpful for
getting warm
um of course Wim Hof the Iceman right
who has the longest
lots of Records you know running above
the polar Circle in in shorts Barefoot
and you know and all of those kind of
crazy things but he's a wonderful human
being who has
understood and taught us
that not only does breathing
and not breathing off and on
um help us of course the old yogis
already did practices like that but the
way he does it it makes a lot of sense
to me
he has taught us that we can
at least influence our biology With Our
intention
and of course there's Dr josephenza and
others who have worked on those issues
as well and that is all very helpful too
but to me the basis is always you know
let's get the biology straight and then
add on some other stuff if we got the
time to do that
and I feel I often don't have the time
if I still want to do things in the
world
how do you spell windhoth
let me put it in here Mr whim
is his first name
and huff is his last name with one f
the ice man he's often called or the Wim
Hof method is is this breathing method
that he's developed you know and he does
these ice baths and and I had already
done
showers with a cold shower last but now
I do only cold showers and I find that
very invigorating every morning I do my
little cold shower
head to toe
wonderful
all right guys so what's in your salad
all of this and more I really wanted to
ask you know what other things can be
put into your salad you know come up
with something you know pineapples
um melons watermelon
um
all kinds of roots right from from lyric
to uh parsnip to you know they can all
be put in your salad Monique what do you
say
cilantro
oh cilantro is of course in my dressing
here too yes
there it is yes
mushrooms seaweed let's say mushrooms
and seaweeds yes we haven't even talked
about mushrooms thank you Wendy yes
mushrooms and seaweed yes yes I did my
um uh master's degree on the immune
system with mushrooms Back 40 years ago
oh congratulations
that's great they're powerful and immune
Builders and now they're just using it
you can get powdered but it's supposed
to be raw you can even get powdered but
I do mushrooms every day yes you do
mushrooms shamanic
when you're breaking up say that again
I've been a wild food hunter in
Wisconsin for 30 years before moving to
Costa Rica and I was a mushroom grower
and I had I sold three different kinds
for about three years in Viroqua but I
had nine kinds planted at my farm when I
sold and came here seven years ago uh I
love mushrooms I feel like I'm a little
mushroom person myself
wonderful wonderful that is so cool yeah
we didn't have much mushrooms when I
grew up in my family so I I had to like
get to using mushrooms I make mushroom
gravies and things like that so mixing
with other things
um but yeah not enough and I certainly
don't do enough seaweed because I've
never quite developed a taste for the
seaweed salads that were first offered
to me and you know that you could buy at
the bar at the at the salad buying
health food stores so I'm sure that a
waste of making seaweed tastier than
than what I've
come across yes
I guarantee it
you can have varieties of seaweed and
I've used it for 70 years dose is my
favorite it is seafood mine too Wendy
you were saying yeah adult is my
favorite too I can guarantee you there
are really great ways I had there was
this woman here where there's all these
uh people from different places here in
Costa Rica she was from Russia and she
made me a seaweed salad and I was so
impressed and when I'm already really
hard to impress I'm pretty good pretty
good Chef I was visiting my uncle in
south southern California and he took me
through this Giant grocery store that
was like an Asian import store and they
had so many different kinds of seaweed
and already like the deli section with
the fresh prepared salads and I I must
have left there with five different
kinds of seaweed salad in my in my uh
basket that I'd never seen or heard of
before in color it grows in different
colors red white and blue it's
incredible the Asians really have the
seaweed culture down you know many of
the Asian countries my daughter was into
Korean food a lot and there's also all
kinds of different seaweeds that I'd
never heard of yes
yeah
so my neighbors are growing spirulina
now my my neighbor just went to the
other side of Costa Rica to learn how to
grow spirulina in a tank and he's been
going there regularly to learn they've
got all their stuff set up and they just
are starting their batch now and I've
bought it from them and ate it and I had
such an incredible physical reaction
whenever I eat seaweed in general but
this was like way more vibrant it
reminded me of Klamath Lake super blue
green algae that I was a distributor of
some 30 years ago a positive reaction
okay that's so good oh my God I felt
like my I was just grounded and I just
like sunk into myself somehow wonderful
wonderful yes wonderful so yeah I want
to learn more about seaweed and what to
do and how to do it so I'd be happy to
hear more learn more and for uh getting
older and helping the brain is lion's
mane
yes a mushroom too is really good I'll
do that too
which mushroom mushroom
oh can you put that in the chat I I
don't think I understand or no no no no
i o n
e s and then a lion's mane yes yes oh
okay yes
um
you can get it at Whole Foods mm-hmm
now you can get it in powder but I don't
know for sure if it's raw in powder but
you can get it as a mushroom very
challenging to find though yeah yeah
most of it was like supplements so to
speak but yeah yeah no I wouldn't take
it in the pill yeah but find Mountain
Rose Herbs I've gotten my cordyceps and
reishi and chaga from them and it's an
excellent quality
awesome yeah again you know more to
learn
and I love those mushrooms that you can
just chop up and throw into either a
salad or you know like I said I make
gravies and or mixes
in my Vitamix
oh I used to make
um for advance
uh the
mushroom Pate raw mushrooms awesome and
then they drop me the recipe
I haven't been doing because I make
um
okay okay guys
I mean I would love to again you know
I'd love I'd love some more seaweed
recipes and some mushroom recipes those
are really the two plant food categories
that I know are so important and I don't
do enough of so I I'm deprived dried
powdered mushrooms I used to often have
excess like if you have mushrooms and
you don't sell them then they don't have
a long they don't live long so
that I became a dehydrator Queen so
dried mushroom powder I use for for
flavoring
um all kinds of things anything I'm
making and you can just sprinkle it on
things and it's just absolutely lovely
sounds awesome
and you can take the you can buy bride
home mushrooms and then grind them up
yeah yeah your blender or your coffee
grinder sure yes yeah
yeah yes so
so much so much fun and of course there
are lots more wild edibles which is also
why why I'm doing the um
the learn to be more self-sustaining
course which includes foraging and wild
harvesting stuff
um
yeah you know I I appreciate very very
much learning about things that I don't
know enough about in those two
categories definitely there are also
plants that grow in in Sweet Water in in
Freaks and pods Etc that's what
spirulina is the algae is it's fresh
water yes
and chlorella is not
yes I believe it is awesome
on the oceans
um Laurel is the green stuff and all
green all plants I believe that's right
but um it's really hard to get to get a
good source where they really do a good
job bricking down the cell wall can't
digest it otherwise you're thinking
chlorophyll nothing chlorella yeah I
know but Wendy was saying that's their
green stuff in all our green plants but
you're thinking chlorophyll I think for
that and chlorella is a particular algae
also right yes yes uh the Japanese
that's correct Japanese have uh are very
good in this but of course they have
that
uh break each other
and it contaminated some of the water
but surely you fade you're fading so
they the Japanese have been doing the
Corella for years they were experts yes
again you know the whole of all of Asia
has been doing seaweed so much better
than any of the rest of the world but
the waters near uh in uh also in China
now Berry contaminated
yeah that's that's of course the problem
for for everything our soils and our
Waters that's why it's so important that
we all preach you know at least eat
everything organic even though you you
know there's the argument oh well that
stuff blows over everything anyway it
still is better because you're making a
statement that you want organic
you're making that consumer statement
and you're forcing the industry to move
into that direction you know I come from
Vernon County Wisconsin which has the
most organic small Family Farms of any
county in the United States uh it's next
to Mendocino County California
and I could safely say 10 years ago
that the whole idea that we could trust
any kind of labeling that's happening is
false it's just gone way way beyond that
really the only way to know if your food
is clean is that you grew it yourself
you Wild Harvest it yourself or you know
who grew it and you're in their Garden
I'm sorry but there is not a package in
the store that I can trust anymore well
yeah that's if you want a hundred
percent there's no hundred percent I
still think it's important that we make
that statement we want organic and we're
going for the better the more we're
going to buy it the only way to do that
is to give them your money which is
supporting what they're doing and that's
why they're there
well of course but we all need to live
and we live in this society and not
everybody is able to live in Costa Rica
I grew my own food in Wisconsin for 30
years before moving here yeah yeah well
that's what I mean not everybody is able
to to do that and and there's so much
else to do in the world and I think we
can still make the better choices and
drive that message further and of course
you know there's a lot more than just
buying organic but it is a very
important part of pushing into that
direction
then the standards will start to change
and then they'll they'll those that are
not having either a third party sort of
certified and so forth I mean at some
point it's going to flush itself out
where as johanna's saying that it will
force them to have the
actual certification or something that
will get a little more Credence into
The Source being more organic than not
um the fraud I mean the
false falsifies angles so far because
competition will root that out as well
the thing is to get the certification it
may take seven years it takes that long
to change the soil and because my
grandmother had that but
had everything organic now one thing
about the organic it will always have
little wormholes in it it will not be
perfect with
Perfection and pesticides on it it grows
huge and it is exactly looking and you
don't want anything that's perfect
looking now now now now you're talking
to a farmer who has grown perfect
vegetables and I have 30 years of photos
to prove it
everything we say is everything we say
is relative to something else and unless
we're speaking on what in what relative
conditions relative to something else
that's meaningless so we really can't
make this
Wendy I don't like those absolutisms oh
yes sorry uh no well it's not
meaningless it's just they're they're
all shades of there is such a thing as
indoor Greenhouse growing where we do
produce perfect fruits because there are
no insects right but then I I I would
immediately say that's not a healthy
living plant in the long run because it
needs real exposure to sunlight it needs
real exposure to the life around it
including the insects greenhouses
that's exactly what they help they don't
they're not lacking sunlight in a
greenhouse a greenhouse means it has
sunlight in fact it can't be a
greenhouse unless it has some
is not the same I mean I've created
greenhouses with uh with a colleague
um but yeah it's it's not the same it's
it's just like saying you know running
on your treadmill in the house is the
same as running under trees Outdoors it
just isn't
there are variations and I mean it's
still better just to run in the house on
your treadmill than not to run at all
that's the other you know again there's
this whole scale of better and it's
always good to go a little better yeah
you can't you can't you can't
um
they can't supersede what what happens
in the wild in nature that's why you
know people are saying you know you want
to get
um the various sources of greens or sea
um nutrients from the the wild waters
that's it versus controlled Waters or a
tank or something like that if you're
gonna do something like ginseng those
the most powerful and
um highest constituents of genocides
coming from the wild ginseng out in the
wild ones got a weather all the various
conditions the stream Sun the wind and
everything else and that's and you they
have certain areas where it's controlled
to kind of similar took a greenhouse but
doesn't have the same vibrancy you don't
get the same impact on the body the
immune system the endurance there's no
substitute to the natural sunlight when
water rain
yeah and again Gary I much appreciate
that explanation
and again it is still better to have the
indoor grown tomato that looks perfect
oh yeah okay
then to have the pesticide ridden one
correct no I mean it's the best I agree
you know there's a broad scale and you
know we all do
one step at a time there's no you know
I'm always saying look I'm still driving
a car I'm sitting on a computer right
now even though I know that emfs and all
kinds of
um exhausts from my car Etc are a
problem but I live in this time in
history I participate and I'm working at
moving this culture in the right
direction that's all right participating
in moving us into the right direction
there are no absolutisms no right planet
Earth you are wonderful in saying that
we're all in the process of growing and
learning and adapting and that if we
arrive at the Perfection we are not
living
okay on this on this beautiful word of
wisdom from Shirley I'm going to close
the what's in your raw salad
Mastermind this has been wonderful and
what an incredibly Lively discussion I
love love it and I thank you all for
being here and I thank you for watching
this whenever you're watching this at a
later time this has been an incredibly
exciting
talk and demonstration and Q a
and see you next time for the next
Mastermind it's probably on
sweets and the sweetness of life and the
sugars that are that are part of life
not the ones that are
healing life but the good sugars
so on the sweetness of life is probably
the next Mastermind so don't
miss it
it will come and you can register in
advance for it as soon as I have it up I
should be happy to send you a recipe for
it awesome please do yes
perfect thank you love you guys see you
next time
thank you thank you have a great
afternoon
thank you for being here and everybody
else who contributed
thank you
all right bless you